Meet Todd Napola. Over the last 25 years, he
has created a commercial real estate empire in Miami,
Florida. When Todd was 25 years old, he drained
his bank account down to zero dollars to buy his
first property. And now he has created one of
the most prominent real estate businesses in all of
South Florida. He brought me to his office to share
some of his secrets on how he was able to
become a real estate tycoon and how he
was able to grow an eight-figure real estate portfolio.
All right, so you're at my office right now.
You said you want to learn about real estate
and property management. Come on, I'm going to
show you. In this interview, Todd revealed to
me the most valuable piece of advice he
was given throughout his career from his billionaire mentor.
The richest people on the planet, I don't
care if you want to talk, if they're in
railroads and oil or technology,
they all invest in real estate.
He walked me through how he was able to
close a $25 million deal this past December. In this
episode, you will learn everything you need to
know to start creating wealth in real estate today.
If someone said to you, they'll sell
you this property for a billion dollars,
but you got to close tomorrow morning, anyone
could find a billion dollars. You got to find
the deal. I'm James Dumoulin, and
this is 10 Questions with a Millionaire.
So how long have you been an entrepreneur for?
I think I've been an entrepreneur my whole life.
I've always had my own businesses and done my
own thing, but this particular company is 22 years old.
And as an entrepreneur, if you were to
go back and you started your first business,
what's the number one piece of advice that
you would tell yourself? What's your best advice
to any entrepreneur starting a business in today's world?
Find a mentor. And I would repeat that 10 times.
I waited a long time to actually find a so-called
mentor, and I was actually at a real
estate convention, and a guy named Gary Rappaport was
sitting there and he was a really cool teacher,
and talks about the whole lecture, and he's an icon
in the real estate business. He's been doing this
a lot longer than me, and he's huge in this
business. And he gives this speech, and I'm blown
away. I'm like, this guy is great. And he said,
what I've done now is I placed my business card
on the corners of this room. Feel free to take my
card and call me anytime, email me, text me. I'm
happy to help anyone. And he said, here's what I
know. By the end of this, all my cards will be
gone, but none of you are going to call me. And he
said, and I find it amazing
because everybody says they want help.
want help but they don't call and i said huh so
i took his card and i wanted to be more proactive
so what i did is he had a booth at
this real estate convention i kind of went and stalked
him out and i was waiting outside his booth
because i wanted to go meet this guy because
he just wowed me and he is an icon in
our business and i was standing and people were actually walking
by like saying what are you doing i'm like i'm
waiting for that guy to stop talking so i can go
meet him the minute he finished talking i went up to
him and i said hi gary my name is todd napola i
really love what you do and i love what you said
i want to take you up on that offer but i don't
have a specific question but i want to ask you if
you would allow me to do something i said what you
do is my dream i said this is what i do
as well but you've been doing a long time and you're very
successful i said can i come to your office see
what you do and i'll take you to lunch and he's
like yeah well you're you're he goes here in
virginia i snow i'm in florida i said but i'll
fly up to do this he goes if you fly up the
only change is i'm going to buy you lunch i got on a
plane i flew up to the airport and i was like i'm
going to go to the airport and i'm going to go to
the airport and i'm going to go to the airport and i'm
going to go to the airport and i flew up to maryland
i flew up to washington dc he was offices in
virginia maryland area i met this guy i went into
his office he didn't spend 15 minutes with me he
spent the entire day and this is a guy with
billions and billions and i mean many billions
of dollars worth of real estate he spent this
whole day with a total stranger he gave me his book
which is part of the reason i wrote a book too
we went to lunch i did insist on buying him lunch
and i stayed in touch with this guy as a mentor
and one of the things he said to
me is why did it take you so long
to find a mentor who does what you want to
do versus mentors who just go to business like i had
mentors who were you know ran a big you know a pr
firm or this but he goes why did it take you so
long and my answer was it was a stupid mistake but
i got one now and i keep in touch with gary and
it's funny because the last time i talked to him
was in december and i said gary i just closed a
25 million dollar deal i'm so excited oh that's
great he goes we just closed one too for 125.
and i was like i know you're not saying to
crush me he's like no i'm saying because keep going
and i'll see him and made our real
estate convention and what i learned from him is
the more successful people are the more
they really want to see other people win
your competition is not necessarily wanting to see you
win but the people who have really made it just
ask them for help they will help you you will
be amazed at how much they'll help you what was the
best financial advice that you've ever received throughout
your lifetime you know i was very lucky
because as i told you earlier i started washing
cars and boats for very wealthy people and what i
learned from that is that the more people who are
wealthy the more they want to help me as a young
kid and maybe they saw a part of themselves
in me and they wanted to give me that value
and what they were telling me back then which
is even more relevant today is don't count other
people's money and so many people are looking
at other people and they're seeing things that
really aren't real and they kind of know it's
not real and i specifically mean now you guys
have social media back then it was you know it was
the cars and boats all over things but a lot of
this stuff isn't real and people get so caught
up in what other people are doing and they're not
really paying attention to what other people have
and keeping up with the joneses and they're buying
things and spending money on things they really can't
afford and i don't want to say stay in your
lane but worry about yourself worry about if
you're good so much of what the young generation
sees today all over the place it's fake and they
know it's fake but they see it and they think it's
real and they're trying to keep up and it's
the young kids like you taking people out for dinners
that you really can't afford because you saw somebody
else do it it's just wrong stay in your
own lane worry about yourself count your own money and
i think that's what people do and i think it's
not gonna be easy but it's gonna be
hard and what's interesting about this is you're gonna
be only able to sell yourself and you're
gonna be able to sell yourself because you're gonna
be able to use your own money and don't
worry about what anybody else is doing just worry
about yourself and it'll work out fine you
start comparing yourself to other people there's always
going to be someone richer there's always going to
be someone faking it more it'll make you feel
insecure because you're gonna go right now i could
go with you on instagram and show you a thousand
kids that look like they're doing great and it
could make you feel bad about yourself worry about
yourself go at your own pace and it'll work out
fine and what was the biggest risk that you've ever
taken throughout your business career the biggest risk i
ever took which obviously i don't want to say
I'm grateful I took and I wasn't even scared
to take it was when I bought my first property.
I was at the time, I was
a stockbroker and I was doing very well.
This was the 1990s, but I knew I wanted
to invest in real estate because as a stockbroker,
you get paid commissions, which means
if there's no trade, there's no money.
And that's great.
People say you make a lot of money, but if
I wanted to go on vacation for a week, I made
zero.
It was commission based.
So I knew I wanted to buy real estate.
So at 25 years old, I bought my first property.
I drained out my entire bank account down to
$50 and it was from six figure amount of
money down to $50.
And I got to the closing table, a
25 year old kid buying my first property.
And this guy at the time seemed old.
I guess he was my age at the time,
but he was probably 45, 50 year old lawyer.
He said, why are you buying this property?
And I told him my plan for the property and
he kind of left and he said, you think this
is that easy?
And then I went and told all my stockbroker
friends, I took all my money and I bought
a property.
And they didn't just laugh at me.
Some of them, they literally bullied me, telling
me how stupid I was to buy this property.
And I went home and I looked in my
bank account and I saw all that money gone.
And back then you used to like
handwrite your account and it said $50.
And I said, you know what?
What's the worst that could happen if I lose everything?
I still have a good job.
However, I bought that property in June for $575,000.
I went, I re-tenanted the whole property.
I cleaned it up.
I got my friends out there, cheap labor.
We painted it.
We made it look nice.
I wrote leases for new tenants.
And in December of that year.
I refinanced that property to price for $800,000.
I got a $600,000 loan.
I got all my money back.
I got all my closing costs back and I
was getting $5,000 a month in free cashflow as
of January, seven months later
for the rest of my life.
And that's been 25 years.
I still own that same property today.
So it was a huge risk, but pays off.
You gotta be willing to take those shots.
What was the number one
book that ultimately changed your business?
What is the number one book that
you think every entrepreneur should read in today's
world?
It's not a business book.
The book that changed my life for
sure and got me on the straight path.
And you know, I mean, not that I had a
unstraight path, but the book that really got me motivated
really was an old school book
by Tony Robbins, Awaken the Giant Within.
And he talks about that and unlimited power.
And these books really get you to a point
where you learn that we're capable of so much
more than we think we are.
But what he always teaches is everybody overestimates what
they could do in one year, but we underestimate
what we could do in five.
And if you scale things out and figure
out and just chunk it, it'll all add up.
But you gotta be patient sometimes.
But he really taught me in those books at
a young age, in my 20s, that you could do
anything.
And that was his story.
If you fast forward to now, there's
a lot of great books out there.
I'm a big reader.
I read, last year I read 60 books.
I'm still reading.
It's the greatest thing you could do because
anyone who writes a book probably has 25,
30 years of experience, and they're gonna
give it to you in 200 pages.
So even if you're a slow reader and
you're gonna read one book a month, you're gonna
get hundreds.
Hundreds of years of experience in the
course of one year from all these people.
So if you wanna be a
doctor, read books written by doctors.
You wanna be a lawyer by lawyers.
You wanna do real estate,
read books by real estate guys.
In fact, I'm gonna give you my book.
I wrote a book all about that,
keeping it real on commercial real estate.
And I tell you what, this
is the perfect example I'm saying.
I'm a guy now, I bought so much
real estate in my days, I've done so much.
The greatest thing I could
do now is helping give back.
So I wrote a book.
I'm gonna give all the proceeds to charity for
this book, and I give the book away like
crazy because I want other people to get involved.
So I'm gonna give you a copy of that book.
I really appreciate that.
I wanna ask you, what would you say
are the top three takeaways that everyone should get
out of this book?
What are the three biggest lessons that you
think people should take away and learn from
this book?
The best three things you could get from that
book is not how handsome I am on the cover.
The top three things you could get out of
that book is no matter what you do, and you
can see this all around.
The richest people on the planet, I don't
care if you wanna talk, if they're in railroads
and oil or technology, they all invest in real estate.
They all wanna have real estate.
It's one of the greatest things you could own.
Whether it's a special house you wanna own
or whether it's a piece of commercial property,
you gotta learn real estate.
The reason being is if you wanna be
the greatest architect or the greatest dentist you could
be, you're not gonna have continued
cash flow in your retirement years.
You're not gonna have something you could
give your kids unless, of course, that's the
same business they want.
You buy one piece of real estate and you
do everything else wrong but pay that one property
off over 25 years, 20 years, you own it.
You're set.
You may not be rich off of one property,
but if you just did one thing right and bought
a piece of property, you could retire.
And a lot of people get to an age where
they're in their 60s, 70s, and 80s and they're broke.
So the younger you are, you should buy property.
That's the most important thing is to get started.
The second most important thing you could learn
from my book is what type of property
works for you.
As I said earlier, take a look at your life.
Take a look at your life.
Different things work for different people.
If you are the dentist, you can't
buy the value-add property because you don't have
time.
If you do have time, there's value-add property.
And the third thing you'll get out of
that book is it's much easier than people think.
Many people come up to me and they
say, oh yeah, but you can't buy commercial property.
It's impossible.
It's very possible.
Just like you know how to manage your apartment
and take care of your own apartment and do
your laundry and take care of things,
owning commercial property is very, very easy.
And I tell everybody when they buy, and you'll
get this out of the book too, buy a property
you could manage yourself.
And learn the business and you'll
see just how easy it is.
And once you buy one, I very rarely ever hear
a person saying I don't want to own a second.
They say I should have done it sooner.
So start early.
So start at your age.
Yeah.
It's kind of like you said, a lot of
people think that it's really hard to get into.
But I feel like there's kind of this misconception that
you have to have a ton of money in order
to buy property and invest in real estate.
But what has been your secret to
creating wealth in real estate throughout your career?
Maybe it has to do with
leveraging capital from not just yourself.
But like, you know, there is that misconception
in today's world that like people think that
in order to invest in or buy
property, they have to have all this money.
Like what would you say to those people?
Well, I would tell anybody who has no
money, no credit and thinks that there's no shot
they could buy a property, go find a deal.
Because I tell this to young people all the time.
We have a very big mall
down the street from us here.
It's called the Aventura Mall.
And it's probably worth, if I guess, $3 billion.
And I say to them, if someone said to
you, they'll sell you this property for a billion
dollars, but you got to close tomorrow
morning, anyone could find a billion dollars.
You got to find the deal.
So if you're young and ambitious.
Go out and find properties that make sense.
There's a line of people 100 miles long that
want to invest in good deals, but they can't
find them.
So if you find a really good deal and
you bring it to me or someone else or somebody
you know with money, the money is easy.
The deal is hard.
So go out and find a deal.
Right.
And real estate is an extremely competitive industry.
So what would you say is the
biggest thing that you've implemented throughout your company
to really stand out against the competition
and be able to find those deals?
What makes us unique is we do it all in-house.
So there are a lot of companies
that want to go out and buy properties.
And specifically doing what we
do and buying larger properties.
The catch is they'll say, I'm buying a property.
I'm going to buy one in Ohio,
one in Arizona, one in New York.
I don't feel you have an edge.
Every property that we own is within 250,
300 miles from where we are right now, which
means I could wake up in the morning,
drive to my property, see what's going on, take
care of what I have to, understand it,
have lunch and drive home, be home for dinner.
Because I have that and I'm local
to my properties, I understand the market.
Now.
Everything we do, we do in-house.
My entire leasing team is here.
My accounting team is here.
My property management team is here.
So we overlap one another.
So this property knows what this property is doing.
And this manager knows what this manager is doing.
When you have everything
in-house, you have absolute control.
We have a ton of tenants.
So because they're all nearby each other, we
have the ability to say from one tenant,
say they have a nail salon and
have a vacancy in another nail salon.
I could ask them for
referrals to how to rent that.
So those synergies go a long way.
What was the biggest deal that you've ever created?
Closed in commercial real estate.
The biggest deal I ever
did was actually this past December.
We bought a property that
had never been on the market.
Same kind of example of what I do.
A father and son built it 50 years ago.
And they built it over 10
years, so 40 to 50 years.
So over 10 years span.
They built 165,000 square feet of shopping centers.
And unfortunately, the grandfather then
passed, the father passed, and
it went down to the heirs.
And like a lot of things, as
it dilutes to multiple people, it got challenging.
So we bought that property in December for $25 million.
Wow.
And I wanted to ask you, what is
your best investment advice to everyone out there?
So let's say someone's in their
career, they're finally starting to save money,
put it to the side.
They're looking to maybe get
into the market, buy some property.
What are those indicators that you look
for in a market that tells you,
now's the time to buy?
You need to buy this property.
What's the secret to investing in real estate?
You gotta go against the grain.
So like I said to you
earlier before, everybody's afraid of office product.
I don't buy office cuz
at this stage in the game,
I'm really good at retail and industrial product.
But everybody's afraid of office.
Nobody wants to buy it.
When I buy a lot of retail,
you probably heard the expression retail is dead.
No one's gonna shop, they're only gonna buy on Amazon.
Well, that proved incorrect.
But if you follow the momentum,
the herd mentality, everyone's saying, well,
now you need to buy multifamily,
you need to buy a house.
That's probably the wrong way to go.
So when people are really scared to make decisions,
that's when you gotta be aggressive.
And when they're very aggressively
buying everything, you better get scared.
So you'll see that play out over time.
So find what you like, and it's always the
right time to buy what you like if it's
a good deal, but don't follow the herd mentality.
Stick to what it is you like,
and over time, it'll do just fine.
What is the biggest mindset change that
is needed in order to become a
multimillionaire?
I believe anyone could be a multimillionaire.
You just gotta believe you wanna be a millionaire, and
you gotta know why you want to be a millionaire.
If you wanna be a millionaire
because you saw something on Instagram or
something like that, and you think
people have a fancy car and
they're millionaires, they may not be.
If you wanna be a
millionaire because you want financial freedom,
you will find a way to do it.
You gotta believe it, and I really believe you could
talk things right into the universe and get them back.
But you gotta have the right why.
If you don't know your why, it won't happen.
If your why is I want a
fancy car and fancy dinner, it won't happen.
If your why is I wanna make sure
I can send my kids to college one day,
I could take care of my parents if need
be, and I wanna go to sleep every night
knowing I'm not worried about next
month's bills, you could get it done.
If your bank account hit zero
tomorrow, right, you went broke tomorrow,
what would be the first step that you
would take to build your empire back and
become financially free again?
You know, a lot of guys say that.
What would happen if you went to zero?
If your bank account goes to zero,
you have built up so much knowledge and
so many contacts, it does get a lot easier.
Which is why you hear about the
guy who has a billion dollar company,
like the guy who said who owns this office building,
we're making another billion dollars.
That second billion dollars doesn't change his life one bit.
He doesn't change in any way.
So at this point, if I lost
everything, the skill sets that I've learned,
forgetting about the hundreds and hundreds
and hundreds of books I've read,
the contacts I have with banks, my reputation
of what I am and what I stand for,
I know I could build it
all back up in no time.
And you think you would get back into
real estate if you had to start over?
100,000%, it's what I love.
And people sometimes say this to me
too, they're like, well, you have spaces,
why don't you open a restaurant?
Why don't you take a vacancy and open this?
That's not what I do,
I don't have passion for that.
I invest in real estate, I
love real estate, I eat, breathe, and
sleep real estate, so it's
exactly what I would do again.